I just received the notification.
刚才接到通知了
The company account will be up
公司账号下个礼拜
and running normally next week.
就能正常运营了
I've got everything
重新上线的这些内容
for the relaunch sorted out,
我也都安排下去了
so there shouldn't be any issues.
不会有什么问题
Meng'an.
梦安哪
I really owe it to you
多亏了有你
for keeping Xinmiao running.
才把新苗给保住了
Thanks.
谢谢
Let's skip the formalities between us.
咱俩就别说这个了
It's been tough for years,
新苗这么多年呢
but we've made it through each challenge.
是关关难过关关过呀
The company's survived,
公司保住了
but it's definitely taken a hit.
但也伤了元气了
They say fortune changes,
这风水轮流转
and that old saying really holds true.
这老话挺有道理的
Look at the investments now.
你看这投资现在
They're all pouring into Blue Ocean.
不都投到蓝海去了吗
We've had investors
是我们这儿
pull out?
又有投资撤了
But I hear Blue Ocean
但我听说蓝海
is backed by Yaohui Co.
拿的是耀辉资本的钱啊
Blue Ocean excels in operations,
蓝海一直是胜在运营的
while we've been strong in content.
我们是胜在内容
Anyway, it's not the end of the world.
大不了咱们拼一拼
We'll push forward and compete.
继续齐头并进呗
Head-to-head.
正面刚啊
I'm afraid I have no strength now.
刚不动了
How?
怎么会呢
We've been working together for so long.
你我搭档这么多年
I'll tell you the truth.
我就给你撂个实底吧
I've been thinking
我现在啊
about quitting.
想退出了
Quitting?
退出
But why?
为什么呀
No particular reason.
不为什么
It's the board's decision.
这是董事会的意见
They want to sell the company.
他们要把公司给卖了
But you're the founder.
你是创始人啊
How can they ask you to leave?
他们怎么能让你退出呢
They want to sell off the company?
还卖公司 卖新苗吗
Being a founder
你个创始人
doesn't mean much here.
他管什么用啊
It's all about what the capital wants.
创始人 你得听资本的
If they want to sell, then they sell.
人家要卖就卖
Who are we to say no?
怎么了
But it might not be so bad.
不过也挺好的
See,
正好
you're on maternity leave.
你休产假嘛
Now you can take the time to relax.
你就踏踏实实地休息
Honestly,
反正我呢
I'm not up for continuing anymore.
是真没心气再干下去了
Just stand by me
你就陪我站好
for the last duty.
最后一班岗吧
Mr Yu.
于总
Wanzhen.
婉真
No, no, no...
不 那个
Wendy.
温蒂总
Got a minute?
有时间吗
I'm always available for you.
你找我 随时有时间
Have a seat.
请
About the acquisition of Xinmiao,
收购新苗的事
what are your thoughts?
你到底怎么想的
Well,
我想啊
I'm thinking of acquiring Xinmiao first,
先把新苗收购下来
then bringing you in
然后就请你
as the investor's representative
作为投资方的代表
to join Blue Ocean.
进驻我的蓝海
Then you, me,
然后你 我
and Meng'an
还有梦安
could team up at Blue Ocean
咱们三个可以在蓝海
and do something big.
干一番大事业
Are you sure about this?
你确定要这么做吗
Mr Zhou is very supportive.
周总非常支持啊
I think it's a solid plan.
我觉得这是个好计划
Indeed, for our investment,
确实对我们投资来说
two leading platforms
两个平台
joining forces
两个头部强强联合
to create a regional unicorn
打造区域独角兽
is really a great move.
确实是一个好计划
Exactly,
没错
it's definitely a win-win situation.
绝对是一个双赢的局面
Our company is fine
但我们公司是没问题
and we won't lose, of course.
肯定不会输
But what about you?
可是你呢
I...
我
If you sign the bet-on agreement,
你要是签对赌的话
it will be a double-edged sword.
那可是一把双刃剑
But if I
但是 如果我
do not sign this agreement,
不签这个对赌的话
Mr Zhou
那么周总
and the other investors
包括另外几家投资公司
won't support me anymore
他就不会再支持我了
or provide additional funding.
他也不会再给我增资了
Our investment terms are strict.
我们的投资条款很苛刻
What if you lose
你要是签对赌的话
after signing this deal?
你要是输了怎么办啊
Are you caring about me personally?
你是在关心我个人吗
I care about you only because
我关心你 是基于对你
you know Blue Ocean too well.
对蓝海的了解
Blue Ocean
蓝海呢
is your brainchild.
是你一手创立的
It's all of your work
它是你这十年的
for the past decade.
全部心血
If this acquisition
如果因为这次扩张
means your loss of control
丧失了对蓝海的控制权
or even being pushed out of Blue Ocean,
甚至被赶出了蓝海
won't you regret it?
你会后悔吗
You're worried about me.
你是在担心我
I...
我
You're our kid's father.
你是孩子的父亲
I have reason to be concerned.
我有理由担心你
Wanzhen, actually,
婉真你说的这些
I've thought
我其实
about this a lot already.
之前就反复地想过
It's basically two choices:
无外乎两条路
either let Blue Ocean grow
要不然我让蓝海发展
or maintain my personal control
要不然就是我个人
over the company.
牢牢地控制住蓝海
So what's your choice?
那你的选择呢
I choose
我选择
to let Blue Ocean grow.
让蓝海扩大发展
You know investment.
你懂投资
I know the Internet.
我懂互联网
Over the past decade,
其实这十年来啊
Blue Ocean and I
我跟我的蓝海
have been facing
一直都面对着
these kinds of challenges and choices.
这样的考验和选择
This time,
这次我想
I need your investment.
争取你们的投资
If I miss
如果我抓不住
such a great opportunity,
这个风口的话
Blue Ocean could stagnate.
我们蓝海将是不进则退
Or even worse,
甚至未来
it could face collapse
会走投无路
with no way out.
或者是彻底毁灭
Since I'm seeking your investment,
既然要你们的投资
I have to take this risk.
我就要承担这个风险
Alright.
行
if you're set on it,
既然你想好了
let's proceed as planned.
那咱们就按计划推进
About what I told you today,
这种话
I won't repeat it again.
我不会说第二遍了
I know.
我知道
You're always like this.
你一向如此
Just like with our divorce, right?
包括咱们俩离婚 对吧
You're getting off track.
你扯远了啊
Wanzhen,
婉真
don't you think my current situation
你不觉得我现在的状态
is perfect
特别适合
for signing this agreement?
签这个对赌协议吗
What do you mean?
什么状态
I'm on my own now.
我孑然一身
You and the kid are gone,
你带着孩子离开了
but we left enough education funds
但是我们给孩子留下了
for our kid.
足够的教育基金
If you were
如果你们
still around,
还在我身边的话
I'd hesitate and hold back.
我会瞻前顾后
I'd never have the guts to fight
我绝对不会像现在
with my back against the wall like this.
背水一战
If Xinmiao is sold,
新苗要卖了
I'll have to leave.
我肯定是要走的
I'm the former boss's
我一前任老板
chosen HR director.
钦定的人力资源总监
I can by no means stay.
不可能留的
Same here.
都一样
New ruler, new officials.
一朝天子一朝臣嘛
Employees like us,
像我们这种
with high salaries,
用人成本又高
not very obedient,
还不太听话
and occasionally tripping up the boss,
偶尔还给老板挖坑的
certainly have to go.
肯定都是留不下的
But you may stay.
你不一定
Why?
为什么呀
You're the content director,
你是内容总监
the core of the company.
这是公司硬核
Who else could take on Xinmiao
估计能收下新苗的
besides Blue Ocean?
除了蓝海还能有谁啊
Well, Mr Yu
那于总
has been trying to poach you, hasn't he?
不是一直想挖你吗
Could be someone else.
有可能是别人呢
Have a bet?
敢不敢打赌
Better not.
那还是算了吧
If it's someone else,
要是别人的话
I might still have a chance.
我还能赖一赖
But if it's Yu Hai,
要是于海
I'd really be out.
估计还真留不下了
Why?
为什么呀
We are friends after all.
那本来就是朋友嘛
Look at me right now.
那我现在这个样子
I still need maternity leave.
还要休产假
I can't occupy this position
不能占着这个地儿
without contributing.
不给人干活啊
That would be awkward even with friends.
那不连朋友都没得做了
Anyway, they can't fire you,
反正他们不能开了你
you're pregnant.
你是孕妇
That's your lifeline.
这就是保命符
Any plans?
有什么打算吗
I'm thinking of
准备预支个
taking a 20-year annual leave,
二十年的年假
traveling the world,
云游四海
and maybe meeting a prince charming.
偶遇郎君
It'd be prefect
最好能遇到个
if I meet someone like Li Lin.
像李临那样的
Or you can just give me
要不然你给我
a photo of Li Lin,
一张李临的照片
and I'll carry it with me.
我带在身上
Think it'll work?
你说能不能管用
Come on.
滚
He's no mascot.
他又不是钟馗
What about you?
你呢
Any plans?
有什么打算啊
What's the use of my plans right now?
我现在打算有什么用啊
I'll just focus
先踏踏实实地
on giving birth first.
把孩子生了吧
Then you should stay home for now.
那你先在家待着吧
When I'm back in charge,
等我重掌大权
we'll achieve greatness again.
咱们再创辉煌
Okay.
好
Aren't you even a little bit disappointed?
真的一点都不失落吗
How could I not be?
怎么可能呢
There she is.
在那儿呢
Meng'an.
梦安
Honey!
老婆
Hello, Meng'an.
你好 梦安
Yiduo.
梅师姐
How did you get here? Took a cab?
怎么过来的 打车
Are you alright?
没累着吧
Yes.
没有
Long time no see.
好久不见
Yes, it's been a while.
是 好久不见
I've been wanting to visit you
我一直都想去看你
but never had the chance.
但一直没有机会
I'm glad you're here today.
今天幸亏你来了
You look great,
你状态真好
and the scarf suits you.
这丝巾戴着也好看
That's sweet of you.
谢谢你啊
He's impressive,
我师哥真厉害
balancing work and life so well.
工作生产两不误
Yunjie loves the chocolates
你送云阶的巧克力
you sent her.
她也特别喜欢
Have you thanked Yiduo?
你谢谢师姐了吗
I did,
我谢了
when I got them.
给我的时候我就谢了
Yes, he thanked me.
谢了 谢了 谢了
How long are you staying this time?
这回回来待几天啊
Do you have time
有没有时间
for a meal at my place?
我请你去家里吃个饭
I'm not sure about
待多长时间
how long I'll stay yet,
还没确定呢
but a meal at your place
不过去家里吃饭
sounds good.
可以啊
Li Lin
我师哥
has never invited me.
就从来没有邀请过我
It's okay.
没事
Don't worry about him.
不用理他
I'm inviting you.
我请你
Great.
好
Boss.
老板
Where are we going so urgently?
你这是突然去哪儿啊
You didn't even tell me.
也不提前告诉我一下
I've still got a ton of work left to do.
我手上一堆活没干完呢
The boss is taking an employee out
老板带员工
for a work event.
出去参加工作活动
Does he need to report to the employee?
还需要向员工报备吗
As long as the boss's plans are good.
老板带的路都对
I was planning to give you a surprise.
我是打算给你个惊喜
What did you mean?
什么意思啊
Another surprise?
又要给我惊喜
You...
你
you'd be better off giving me
你还不如给我来点
something real instead.
实实在在的呢
Chen Wanzhen,
陈婉真
why have you turned
你怎么现在
into this kind of person?
变成这样了呀
Here's your gift.
给你的礼物
A VIP invitation to the investor summit.
投资人峰会的邀请函
For me?
你给我的吗
Thanks, boss.
谢谢老板啊
No problem.
不客气
Does this count as a surprise?
算不算惊喜
But I'm afraid
但是我
I'm not really qualified for this.
不够格吧
As long as
我这个推荐人
your reference is qualified.
够格就可以了呀
There's a forum
峰会呢
at the summit that I need to attend.
有个论坛我要参加
As for you,
你呢
you'll be carrying my bag
给我拎包
and getting a good look around.
我带你好好见识见识
Sure, I'll take good care of your bag.
行 我一定给你看好包
Why did you suddenly
你今天怎么
find time to see me today?
突然有时间来找我啊
Just wanted to take a walk with you.
就想跟你出来溜达溜达
Take a walk?
溜达溜达
There's nothing else going on?
不会是有什么事吧
You figured it out.
看出来了
I'm not blind.
我这点还看不出来
Xinmiao
新苗
is being sold.
要被卖了
Why?
为什么
The industry is already in a downturn,
行业本来就不景气
and with the mess
再加上黄思思
Huang Sisi caused,
闹出来的这个事情
Zhang is probably taking the blame.
老张应该是担责任了
He told me today
他今天跟我说
that the board wants him out.
是董事会想让他退
It looks more like
我看着
he's resigning in disgrace.
更像是引咎辞职的
Why so suddenly?
怎么这么突然啊
With Zhang gone, what happens to you?
那老张走了你们怎么办
We'll just manage through the transition.
先过渡吧
But Rachel and I,
但我跟瑞秋这种
we won't be staying for sure.
肯定是留不下的
Let's not worry about that for now.
先不管那么多
We should focus
我们就踏踏实实地
on getting the baby born.
把孩子先生了
I'll be here with you.
我陪你
Now it's my turn to be unemployed.
这回轮到我要失业了
That makes me feel better.
这下我就平衡了
We're leaving now.
那我们先走了
Honey,
老婆
the small stuff is done.
小件装完了
It'd be a shame not to take the big stuff.
大件不拉可惜了啊
What's the shame?
有什么可惜的呀
It was customized for the villa.
本来也是为别墅定制的
Now that we're moving,
搬了
where will it even fit?
能放哪儿去
Just leave it for the next owner.
留给下一家吧
Alright,
好
you're my boss.
听我媳妇的啊
No, no, no.
别别别
Don't say that.
你别听我的
You followed my advice too closely.
你以前就是太听我的
And now we've lost this home.
把这家都给听没了
Talk about this house,
你说这房子
how long have we actually lived here?
才住了多久呀
Why do we have to move?
怎么就要搬家了呢
Honey.
老婆
Don't.
别
I'm just saying.
我就这么一说啊
Don't take it to heart.
你千万别往心里去
It's my fault.
是我不好
I shouldn't have clung to you,
之前我总是黏着你
making you stay home
让你每天守着我
with me everyday
守着这个家
and neglect your work.
都顾不上工作了
It's all my fault.
要怪就怪我
No, my fault.
怪 怪我
Honey, it's my fault.
老婆 都怪我
Honey.
老公
You know what?
你知道吗
When you said wanting a divorce from me,
你之前说要跟我离婚
and talked about selling this house,
要把这房子卖掉的时候
I was furious.
我可生气了
In a moment of anger,
我当时就赌气
I thought,
说
fine, if you want a divorce, so be it.
离就离
I'll just have my parents
大不了我把我爸妈
move in with me.
一块儿接过来住
It'll be better than the old house.
那不比老房子强呀
But then I thought,
可是后来我一想
what's so good about this house?
有什么好的呀
When we moved in,
你说这房子咱一住进来
all this trouble started.
这堆破事
First, Haoze's mom divorced.
先是浩泽妈妈离婚
Then...
然后
then I hired someone to check on you.
然后我又找狗仔查你
It's all been a mess,
这作来闹去的
leading to this situation.
就搞成现在这个样子
So, this house
所以这房子呀
isn't worth it at all.
一点都不好
Honey,
老婆
I'll move back sooner or later.
我早晚会搬回来的
Why would you move back?
谁让你搬回来的
Are you out of your mind?
是不是有毛病
I'm telling you,
我告诉你啊
even if we have money,
以后就算有钱
we're not moving back.
也不许搬回来
This house is nothing
这房子有啥好的
but a headache.
看着就闹心
I've made you suffer.
让你跟我受苦啦
As if I never suffered with you.
我没跟你受过苦呀
Didn't we go through tough times together?
咱俩不是一起苦过来的
You're like my sister,
你跟我姐似的
saying I can't handle hardship.
说我受不了苦
Well, I showed her that I can.
我就受给她看
Get in the car.
上车
Come on, Jia Haowen
上车啊 贾浩文
Coming, sweetheart.
来了 媳妇
I'm coming.
来了
Let's go.
出发
Don't rush.
你不用着急
Look at all your sweat.
你看这一身汗出的
They'll be here soon.
一会儿就到了
I forgot to bring tissues again.
我又忘带纸了
The vegetables today are very fresh.
今天的蔬菜很新鲜的
Yes, they are.
是的
We have plenty of meat at home.
我啊 家里荤菜都有
Really?
是吗
Xu,
老许
why are you two just standing here?
你俩站在这儿干吗呢
Waiting for my youngest daughter.
等我小女儿
She's coming back to move back in
一会儿我小女儿和女婿
with our son-in-law.
搬回来住
I thought your youngest daughter
你小女儿
was living in a big villa.
不是住大别墅吗
Why are they moving back?
怎么就搬回来住了
Look, Xu got sick.
这不老许生病了吗
They insist on
他们俩非要
moving back to take care of him.
搬回来照顾他
I tried to stop them, but they ignored me.
我劝都劝不住
You don't know how lucky you are.
你呀 身在福中不知福
Look how filial these two kids are.
两个孩子多孝顺哪
Exactly.
就是啊
See you later.
回见啊
Alright, bye.
好 好 走了啊
Bye.
好
They're really lucky, those two.
真有福气 他们两个
Yes, they are.
是的呢
We're not so fortunate.
我们就没这个福气
No, we're not.
没有 没有的
Has the car turned in yet?
车拐进来了吗
I haven't seen it.
没看见呢
Xin said it has.
心心说拐进来了呀
It has turned in.
拐进来了
Here they are!
来了
I saw them.
来了 来了 来了
Jia Haowen, play it cool.
贾浩文你给我忍住了啊
No tears,
不许掉眼泪
got it?
听见没
Why are you out here?
怎么都到门口了呀
Waiting for you.
等你们呢
Here.
来
Come.
快来
Dad.
爸
Mom.
妈
Welcome
欢迎
home.
回家
Dad.
爸
Dad's here.
有爸在
It's good you're back.
回来好
Come on, come.
来来 来来 来
Let's go home.
回家
That's good.
回来就好
As long as you're back.
回来就好啊
Help your auntie move stuff.
帮你小姨搬东西去
Let's go.
走走走
Okay.
好
Sister.
姐
Mom.
妈
Good thing you're back.
回来就好啊
You're back.
回来就好
That's good.
回来啦
Don't cry.
别哭啦
Have some corn.
吃个玉米啊
Daddy's back.
爸爸回来了
Have some corn with your daddy,
跟你爸爸一起吃玉米
okay?
行不行
What's this?
那这个是什么
That's cabbage.
这是大白菜
Cabbage.
大白菜
They'll be back soon.
马上回来了啊
Your daddy and mommy
爸爸 妈妈
Come on, look
来来来 你看看
They're back.
回来了 回来了
Haowen, hurry up.
浩文 你快点
Hurry up and come here.
快点过来
Give me a hand.
搭把手
I'm all hands on deck here.
我这几个手呢
I'm babysitting your kid.
我还得看孩子
Mind your own kid.
自个儿孩自个儿看着啊
Come on, your daddy's back.
来来来 你爸爸回来了
Daddy's back.
爸爸回来了
Love you.
爱你哟
Daddy.
爸爸
Dad.
爸
Daddy, I missed you
爸 我想你了
Missed daddy, huh?
想爸爸了哈
Sweetheart.
宝宝
Love you.
爱你哟
Little Watermelon.
小西瓜
Haowen's not feeling well.
浩文难受
That's normal.
正常
He wouldn't have come back with me
要不是到了万不得已
unless it was absolutely necessary.
他不会跟我回爸妈家的
Does his mom
你们俩这事
know about this?
他妈妈知道吗
I didn't tell Haowen to inform her.
我没让浩文跟我婆婆说
She's getting up there in age.
不想让老人家
I don't want to stress her out.
着急上火的
But you can't keep it hidden forever.
那这事也瞒不住啊
We'll keep it secret as long as possible.
能瞒一天是一天吧
What are you planning to do?
你俩有什么打算啊
I'm going to look for a job.
我要出去找工作
At least get something to do.
起码先动起来
Haowen
之前
has taken on so much before.
浩文扛了这么多事
I want him to have some rest
我想让他在家里
at home for now.
让他缓一缓
You want to go back to work?
你想出去工作啊
I support you.
姐支持你
What kind of job are you looking for?
想找个什么样的工作
I can ask around for you.
回头我帮你去问问
I'm not sure yet,
没想好
but I have an old classmate
但是我有个老同学
who runs an art institute.
开了个美术机构
I think
我想
it's related to my background
跟我服装设计
in fashion design.
还算是对口
I'll check it out
回头我上他那儿
and see.
先去问一嘴
Okay.
好
Xin,
心心啊
there's something
有几句话
I want to remind you about.
姐还是想嘱咐嘱咐你
Every family has its own challenges
虽然家家有本难念的经
and ways
各家相处的方式
of handling things,
也不一样
but there's one thing
但是有一点
that's pretty universal:
还是大同小异的
at times like these, you need to be
越是到这个时候
especially considerate of his feelings.
你越要在意对方的感受
Everything
万事
should be discussed together.
两个人要商量
It's not the time to show your capability.
现在不是显示你有多行
but about giving each other
而是要给予对方
more respect
更多的尊重
and trust.
和信任
Got it?
知道吗
You're both still young,
你们还都挺年轻的呢
and things will work out.
会好的
Come here. Let me hug you.
来姐抱抱
The beef is ready.
来 牛肉好了
Dear, hurry up and eat
媳妇 快点赶紧捞
before it's all gone.
一会儿他们都抢没了
What do you want to eat?
你要吃什么
I'll get it for you.
姑姑给你捞
Did you hear? Don't get it yourself.
听见没 你别自己去弄
Xiongxiong, come on.
熊熊 来
Come, Yunjie.
来 云阶
Come on.
来来来
He doesn't like spicy food.
他不敢吃辣的
Yunjie, Yunjie,
云阶 云阶
Hurry up.
快快快
Mom, Mom.
妈 妈 妈
Here you go. This is yours.
来来来 这就是你的
Everything's ready.
都 全好了 全好了啊
Let's have a toast.
一起喝一个吧
Let's do it.
来
Okay?
好不好
Dad, Mom.
爸 妈
I hope you stay healthy.
大家健健康康啊
This way, Mr Zhou.
这边 周总
Thank you.
谢谢
Mr Zhou, please take a look here.
看下这边 周总
Mr Zhou,
周总
what are your criteria
请问您投资一个项目的
for investing in a project?
判断标准是什么呢
Yes, Mr Zhou.
是啊 周总
There are many criteria.
标准有很多
But a project
但是一个符合
that meets all the criteria
所有标准的项目
isn't necessarily a good one.
不一定是个好的项目
The key is to find something
首先要找到一个
that really resonates with you.
打动你的点
That's the core and soul
这才是一个项目的
of the project.
核心和灵魂
You must be Wendy?
你就是温蒂啊
Yes.
是
I'm Wendy Chen from Yaohui Co.
我是耀辉投资的温蒂陈
Here's my business card.
这是我的名片
Chen Wanzhen.
陈婉真
I know you.
我知道你
You're quite famous.
你很有名
You're flattering me.
你过奖了
Well,
行了
today I finally see
我今天算是知道了
what the goddess
周耀喜欢了
that Zhou Yao has admired
十年的白月光
for ten years looks like.
原来长这个样子
I hope I didn't disappoint you.
希望没有让你失望
Wendy.
温蒂
But I must say,
不过我得说
you're really gorgeous.
你确实挺漂亮
Thanks.
谢谢啊
Wendy.
温蒂
I've been waiting for you.
我等你半天了
Mr Zhou.
周总
Here, give me the bag.
来 包给我
I'll hold it for you.
我给你拿着
No, no, it's fine.
不用 不用 不用
Just cooperate, please.
配合一下 配合一下
What romantic debt have you gotten into?
你又欠了什么桃花债啊
Romantic debt?
什么桃花债
An admirer.
一个追求者
Wendy,
温蒂
there's still some time
现在离论坛开幕
before the forum starts.
还有点时间
How about we
我们
take a walk on the lawn
要不要到外面草坪上去
and get some fresh air?
散散步 透透气啊
No, no,
不了不了
I still have a report to finish.
我还要写报告呢
We're already here, so let's go.
来都来了 走嘛
I really can't.
真的不去了
Work comes first.
工作第一啊
Wendy.
温蒂
Mr Zhou.
周总
I didn't expect
我真是没想到啊
you'd like this style.
原来你喜欢这一款啊
Good taste.
品味不错
She's quite beautiful.
蛮漂亮的
What did you talk about with her?
你刚才跟她都说什么了
Not much.
没说什么
But it seems like your goddess
不过我看你的白月光
isn't too fond of you.
她好像不怎么待见你吧
What goddess?
什么白月光
Mr Zhou,
周总
what did that woman
刚才那个女的
say to you?
跟你说什么了
Boss,
老板
I'll cover for you,
我帮你打掩护归帮你
but remember,
但是呢
we're just
我们只是
employee and boss,
员工跟老板的关系
right?
对吧
So, what kind of relationship
那你觉得
do you think
我们应该
we should have?
是什么样的关系
Let's keep it simple.
简单一点喽
She's the one.
就是那个
The famous Wendy
大名鼎鼎的温蒂
I heard
听说
she's Zhou Yao's goddess
她就是周耀喜欢了
for ten years.
十年的白月光
Work is work,
工作归工作
but I don't want to mix work
那我不想把工作
with personal life.
跟生活混在一起
I get it.
我懂
You want to prove yourself
就是想用工作
through work,
来证明自己
not have
而不想
your personal life
被别人议论
gossiped about.
自己的私生活
Exactly.
对
Well, it might be a bit late for that.
那有点来不及了
Chen Wanzhen.
陈婉真
Don't joke around.
别开玩笑
No, don't go. I haven't finished talking.
不 别走 话没说完呢
Chen Wanzhen!
陈婉真
Do you want to be a partner?
你想不想当合伙人
Here's the partner badge.
这是合伙人徽章
Starting tomorrow,
从明天起
we're not just
我们就不是
boss and employee anymore.
老板和员工的关系了
I wanted to surprise you
我本来想给你个惊喜
and let everyone know
让所有人都知道
your new role,
你的身份
but you ran off faster than a rabbit.
但你跑得比兔子还快
Why are you running away?
你跑什么跑
Sorry, sorry. I...
对不起 对不起 我
I thought...
我以为
-I thought... -Thought what?
我以为 你以为什么
-You thought too much.
我以为 你想多了吧
-Take it? -I'm not...
接受 我没
So, what now?
那怎么着
Do I need to beg?
需要我跪下来吗
Please, please, don't!
求你了 求你了
No, no,
别别别
you, you really...
你真的 你
You really scared me.
你吓死我了
If you wanted to promote me,
你说给我升职
you could've just said so.
不就得了吗
Why scare me like that?
你干吗那么吓人呢
I wasn't trying to scare you.
我没吓你
I was scaring them.
我是 吓她们
I get it.
我明白了
You used me as a tool.
你又拿我当枪使
What do you mean, used you?
我什么又拿你当枪使
It was a win-win,
我本来这就是一鱼两吃
wasn't it?
对吧
I surprised you
给你一个惊喜
to make you happy,
让你开心
and scared her off
给她一个惊吓
to let her go.
让她知难而退
Isn't that
这不是
a brilliant move?
挺好的吗
Thanks, Zhou Yao.
谢谢你啊 周耀
You deserve it.
你应得的
Stop just drinking porridge.
别光喝粥
Eat the egg too.
把鸡蛋吃了
Slow down,
慢点 慢点 慢点
don't choke.
别噎着
Xin,
心心
why isn't Haowen having breakfast again?
浩文怎么又不吃早餐哪
He's not hungry, let him be.
他不饿呗 让他去
How can he not be hungry?
他怎么能不饿呢
Here, take him some food.
那个 你给他带点去
He's a grown-up now.
他这么大人了
Just leave him.
你别管了啊
I'm going grab my stuff.
我收拾东西了
Xu.
老许
Since Haowen
你说浩文
came back,
回来这么长时间了
he's been so quiet,
一天到晚
just staying in his room all day.
闷到屋里也不说话
Maybe you should talk to him
你要不找他聊一聊
or take him out for a bit?
带出去转一转
Auntie.
姨啊
I think my cousin-in-law
我看这表妹夫啊
is really good with Little Watermelon.
对小西瓜真是上心呀
I've never seen a man
我还真没见过
who takes care of babies so well.
这么会带孩子的男人
I heard
我听说呀
there are many men now
现在有很多的男人
who stay at home with kids,
专门在家带孩子
called stay-at-home dads.
叫全职爸爸
No, Lanxiang,
不是 兰香
Haowen
那浩文
can't be a stay-at-home dad.
怎么能当全职爸爸呀
He's too capable for earning money.
他那么能干
He can't just stay home;
他 他不能在家待着
he'd get used to a lazy life.
人会待废的
That's true.
也是啊
See...
你看
No, no, no.
不行 不行
So what should we do?
你说怎么办嘛
Think of something.
想个法子
The short video you showed me
你给我看的那个小视频
is quite motivational, isn't it?
不是挺那个励志的吗
Send him.
发给他
Okay, okay.
行行行
I'll send it to the group chat,
我不能单发他
not just to him directly.
我就发群里
He might have overthought.
要不然他有想法了
Done.
发了
The hand's getting steadier, huh?
这手越来越有准了哈
Let me show you.
我给你表演一下
Good.
行啊
What are you doing?
干吗呢
What's the matter?
怎么了 怎么了
What's all this random stuff
往家庭群里
you posted
发的什么
in the family chat group?
乱七八糟的东西啊
What's wrong with it?
怎么了
How would Haowen think?
这让浩文看了怎么想啊
I just wanted to
我这不是
encourage him.
想给他鼓励鼓励吗
You don't know.
你不知道
When you're not around,
你不在家的时候
he doesn't even leave the house
他连门都不出
or talk to anyone.
也不跟谁说话
It's really scary.
太吓人了
So
所以呢
you're just checking up on him,
你就嘘寒问暖的
by bringing him food and drinks.
送吃送喝的
I knew it.
我一猜就知道
When I was studying,
我读书的时候就是
and doing my homework
我在那儿写作业呢
you'd come in
一会儿进来一下
asking what's for lunch
中午吃什么
or dinner.
晚上吃什么
It was annoying.
烦不烦呀
You're putting pressure on him
你这样是给他压力
with all this attention.
他有心理负担
I didn't mean to pressure him.
我没想给他压力
Over-caring becomes pressure.
过度地关心就是压力
Now It's my fault for caring about him.
关心还关心错了
Here you go again.
你看你
I didn't say it's your fault.
没说你错
It's not.
你没错
Just let him
你就是让他一个人
be alone
自己在屋里待会儿
in the room
清静清静
to think about
让他想一想
what he wants to do next.
今后要做什么
If he wants food or drink,
他要想吃想喝
he'll come out.
他会出来的
Don't disturb him.
你不要去打搅他
Is that okay?
可以吗
Okay.
行
Okay. I'll go now.
行 那我走了啊
By the way,
对了
well,
那个
if my mother-in-law calls,
我婆婆要是打电话来啊
don't tell her anything.
什么都别跟她说
Just say
就说
everything's fine.
都挺好的
Everything's fine.
都挺好
Don't forget it.
记住了啊
Your wife
你老伴啊
almost slipped up last time.
上次差点说漏嘴了
Keep an eye on her.
你管管她
I'm leaving now.
走了啊
Xiongxiong, hurry up.
那个熊熊快点啦
Xiongxiong, hurry up!
熊熊 快点快点
I still think
我觉着
you should talk to him.
你还是得去找他聊一聊
Your hands are getting good.
手利索了
Come on.
阿妹 来
Let's try this.
咱俩翻一下
You did it the wrong way.
方法不对
Yiduo.
一朵
No rush.
不着急表态
You can think it over some more.
你可以再好好想想
Li Lin,
师哥
I can responsibly say that
我负责任地说
this plan
就这套方案
is one of the most complete
在国内没有几个人
in the country.
能做得这么完整
So you're
所以你
the best choice for me to partner with.
是我合作的不二人选
But doesn't Mr Ma
这马院长
want to work with you too?
不是也想跟你合作
You can partner with him.
你可以跟他合作嘛
Ma isn't suitable.
老马不行
He's just like me,
他跟我一样
stuck in an ivory tower.
都待在象牙塔里
What I need
我需要的是
is a practical partner
你这种实干型
with market experience like you.
有市场经验的合作者
I think you should work
我觉着你还是和马院长
with Mr Ma.
合作吧
I...
我
I really can't go to Beijing.
实在是北京去不了
Why not?
为什么
Meng'an doesn't let you go?
梦安不同意
Let me be honest with you.
我就跟你说实话吧
Meng'an is of advanced maternal age.
梦安是高龄产妇
In three months,
还有三个月
the baby will be born.
孩子就要出生了
When our first child was born,
之前老大出生的时候
I had just graduated from grad school,
我因为研究生毕业
so I was busy with work.
忙着工作
Meng'an basically took care of everything
基本上三岁之前
until the child was three years old.
都是梦安带着的
Now, with the second baby coming,
这次老二马上要出生了
I
我
don't want to miss out again.
不想再缺席
This time I'm back in the country
我这次回国
to set up a large lab,
筹备大型实验室
which is a big opportunity for me,
是我的一个机会
and for you too.
对你也是一次机会
At our age,
咱们都这个岁数了
there aren't
事业上
many chances left for career advancement.
留给咱们的机会不多了
Don't you want to
难道你就不想
seize this one
抓住这一次
and prove yourself?
证明一下自己吗
What you're saying
你说的
is indeed tempting,
的确诱惑力很大
but, Yiduo,
但是一朵
I'm really sorry.
真的不好意思
I just can't say yes.
我没法答应你
There's nothing more important
这世界上没有什么比家
than family.
更重要的了
Sorry.
抱歉
This is appetizing.
这个开胃
See if he eats it. Go.
你看他吃不吃 去
Haowen being so closed off
你说浩文老这么闷着
isn't good.
不是回事啊
He might end up sick from it.
得闷出病
I'm talking to you.
跟你说话呢
Haowen's not coming out.
这浩文老不出来
What should we do?
怎么办呢
Auntie,
姨
look.
看
He hasn't eaten a bite.
一口没吃
Xu,
老许
can't you do something?
你能不能管点事
Go talk to him.
你去跟他谈一谈
I'll get some more water.
我再去加点水
The bird in the cage
那笼里的鸟
really wants to fly out, doesn't it?
它多想往外飞呀
Haowen.
浩文
Dad.
爸
Come on. Let's get some fresh air.
跟我出去透透气
I'm playing with the baby.
看孩子呢
Come in.
进来
Haowen.
浩文
Go out for a stroll with your Dad.
你跟你爸出去转转
Lanxiang and I can handle the baby.
孩子 我和兰香看
Dad,
爸
I disappointed you.
都怪我让您失望了
But you've had your moments of glory.
但是你辉煌过啊
Your mom and I
我跟你妈
often talk about you.
经常在背后聊你
We're really proud of the life
说我跟你妈俩
we're living now.
现在能过上这种日子
Honestly, Haowen,
坦白地说 浩文
you've played a huge part in that.
你功不可没
You've supported us financially,
你在经济上关怀我们
giving us all you have,
有多少钱就花多少钱
without ever hiding.
从来不藏钱
Your brother-in-law
你姐夫
has been a great support emotionally.
从精神上关怀我们
You know,
我们老两口
our neighbors,
现在过的这日子
my friends
左右邻居
and fishing partners,
我那些朋友 鱼友
they all envy us.
人都羡慕啊
You've heard the old saying:
这老话不说了吗
a good daughter
说 有好姑娘
means a good son-in-law.
那是因为有好姑爷
Your mom and I
我跟你妈俩
have always been proud of you,
一直就是以你为自豪
never seeing you
也没拿你当姑爷看过
as just a son-in-law
就觉得你是
but as our own son.
我们的儿子
They say a son-in-law is like half a son,
什么一个姑爷半拉儿啊
but to me,
我觉得
half a son-in-law is like a whole son.
半拉姑爷一个儿
Don't blame yourself.
你不要自责
Business
做生意这个东西
has its ups and downs.
那不就是有赔有赚吗
Even the best in business
你神仙你做生意
also have to
他也不能
experience losses, don't they?
光赚钱不赔钱哪
I've heard from my fishing friends that
我还听那些鱼友跟我说
a true businessman
说真正会做生意的人
doesn't just make money,
不光是会赚钱
he knows how to handle losses too.
你还得会赔钱
Losing money is just part of the process
赔钱是为了啥
to make more in the long run.
是为了赚钱
I think
那我还觉得
you've reached
你现在已经到了
a mature business mindset,
儒商的思维了都
haven't you?
是不是
I've never been disappointed in you.
我从来对你没有失望过
Every man has to
那你说一个男人
face some challenges
这一辈子
in his life.
你怎么得经历点啥吧
Don't be hard on yourself.
别内疚
No matter how much money
其实一个人
you make
你挣多少钱
or what position you hold,
当多大官
in the end, what matters most
到最后什么对你最重要
is family.
家